ラジオや会話 ハートでつかめ 英語の極一行詞の大西 博人です
さあ 金曜復習会 頑張っていきましょう
Hey everyone, it's Friday. You know what that means. It's time to review. This is Akina Rosa.
And I'm David Evans. That's right, everyone. It's review day. Yay!
それでは早速始めていきましょう
Lesson 125
今週のリビュー 金曜日は復習会です
最初のコーナーはこちら
リスニングチャレンジ
OK
Let's review this week's dialogues
Listen to the questions
and pick which one of the three options
is the correct answer
Let's start with Monday's dialogue
OK guys, here's the question
What did Hiroki find?
A. Lots of seats
B. A picture of someone he knows
or C. A new menu item
Here we go.
いらっしゃい。
Well, look who's here.
Hiroki. Long time, my friend.
Hi, Carolyn. Good to see you again.
Where have you been all this time?
Well, I've been busy with lots of things.
Have a seat.
What are all these pictures? Are these all your customers?
Yeah, they started putting up photos of themselves a few years ago.
Wait a minute. This one is Barbara.
You know her? She eats here almost every week.
She does?
Yes, recently at least.
Did you get that okay?
Let's go over the question one more time.
What did Hiroki find?
A. Lots of seats.
B. A picture of someone he knows.
答えは
質問は
A. たくさんの席
B. 知っている人の写真
C. 新しいメニュー
答えはB. 知っている人の写真となります
OK. Now let's move on to Tuesday's dialogue.
Let's check out the question.
What did Aoi do on the weekend?
A. She went out with her grandparents.
B. She bought some sandwiches.
C. She went to the park alone.
Listen up!
Hi, Renji. Wow, you look like you got some sun.
Do I? Well, I was running outside at the sports festival.
did you win any races i came in second in one of them how was your weekend ollie pretty busy i was spending time with my grandparents they don't get out much really what did you do i made sandwiches for them and we went to the park that's great my dad says to help others is to help yourself your dad's right
all right how did you do
Let's check out that question one more time.
What did Aoi do on the weekend?
A. She went out with her grandparents.
B. She bought some sandwiches.
Or C. She went to the park alone.
答えは?
A. She went out with her grandparents.
質問は、Aoiは週末何をした?
A. 祖父母と出かけた。
B. サンドイッチを買った。
C. 公園へ一人で出かけた
答えはA. 祖父母と出かけたとなります
Alright everybody, next is Wednesday's dialogue
Here's the question
Why do the two people go to the pub?
A. They are lonely
B. They are hungry
or C. They are lost
Listen carefully
ここには車がないよ、アントン。
馬と荷物だけだよ。
たくさんあるよ。
俺はクレイジーなことを言うかもしれないけど、
僕たちはタイムワープを経験したと思うよ。
あなたの説明を受けられないよ。
まあ、1800年代にいるように見えるよ。
誰かと話すべきだよ。
僕はお腹いっぱいだ。
食べ物を見つけよう。
そこにいる人が説明できるかもしれない。
そこを見て。
パブみたいだね。
They should have good food.
Anything will do. I'm starving.
Yeah, me too.
How'd you do?
Let's check out the question one more time.
Why do the two people go to the pub?
A. They are lonely.
B. They are hungry.
Or C. They are lost.
答えは?
B. They are hungry.
質問は、なぜ二人はパブに行く?
A. 寂しいから
B. お腹が空いているから
C. 道に迷っているから
答えはB. お腹が空いているからとなります
Alright and last up is Thursday's dialogue
First let's check out the question
Which of the following is true?
A. The man wants to buy something for his cat
B.
The woman thinks Umi loves to eat fish.
The man doesn't like cat toys.
Here we go.
Hello, sir. How may I help you today?
Oh, hi. I'm looking for a birthday present.
For your dog or cat?
Uh, for my cat Umi.
Oh, is Umi a he or a she?
Umi is a she, and she is kind of picky.
うーん、このフィッシュドアはどうだろう?
キャットはこれを遊びに行くのが大好きだよ
うーん、わからない
うみはこれを早く遊びに行くかもしれない
OK、では、キャットトイレの大きな選択があります
ありがとう、私は見つけます
はい、わかりましたか?
もう一度、質問を見てみましょう
次の質問はどれが正しいか?
A. The man wants to buy something for his cat
B. The woman thinks Umi loves to eat fish
C. The man doesn't like cat toys
答えは
A. The man wants to buy something for his cat
質問は次のうち正しいのは
A. 男性は自分の猫に何か飼いたい
B. 女性はウミが魚を食べるのが大好きだと思っている
C. 女性はウミが魚を食べるのが大好きだと思っている
男性は猫用のおもちゃが好きじゃない
答えはA
男性は自分の猫に何か飼いたいとなります
さあリスニングチャレンジ出来はいかがでしたでしょうか
英語を学習していると出来が良かったり出来が悪かったり色々します
その日の調子もありますからね
でもしっかりと続けていただいている間に安定して出来が良くなってくるわけですよ
頑張ってください
Say it in English
今週練習した表現を使って 会話の実践練習をしましょう
OK Here is the first situation
Imagine this
あなたのパートナーは 早朝から夕方まで
実質で動画を見続けています
長時間動画を見るのは 目によくありません
外食に誘ってみましょう
例えば
ねえ 動画を長時間見るのは 目によくないわよ
外に行って夕食を取らないすぐ近くに良いお寿司屋さんを見つけたの など
3品と差し上げておきましょう 夕食を取るこれは have dinner と言います
そしてすぐ近くにいろいろな言い方がありますがここでは around the corner というフレーズを使ってみましょう
もう一度セチュエーションを確認します あなたのパートナーは早朝から夕方まで実質で動画を見続けています
長時間動画を見るのは目に良くありません
外食に誘ってみましょう
例えば
ねえ動画を長時間見るのは目に良くないわよ
外に行って夕食を取らない?
すぐ近くにいいお寿司屋さんを見つけたの
など
さあパートナーは動画に夢中ですよ
うーふっふっふーふっふー
あなたならどのように言いますか?
それではここでローザさんの答えを聞きましょう
では内容を順番に確認しましょう
ねえ動画を長時間見るのは目に良くないわよ
4月のレッスン2で学習した文です。覚えていましたか?
動詞ing系の長いフレーズも主語の位置に置けば主語となりますよ。
外に行って夕食を取らない、すぐ近くにいいお寿司屋さんを見つけたの。
why don't weは何々しませんか?主語がweであるため、
提案しています
Why don't you なら何々してはどうでしょう
相手への提案となります
それではローザさんの答えを
もう一度聞きましょう
Hey, watching videos for long hours
isn't good for your eyes
Why don't we go out and have dinner?
I found a good sushi bar around the corner
Alright, let's move on to the next situation
Imagine this
友人がまた財布をなくしました 最近売っている便利な装置の利用を進めてください
例えば財布をまたなくしたの今月2回目だよ あなたの電話から物の位置を突き止めることを可能にするあの装置について聞いたことがある
あなたの財布にそれを入れてみたら など
ヒントを差し上げておきましょう 場所を突き止めるこれはローケイトと言います
そして可能にする enable 装置道具これはギャジェットとおっしゃってみてください
もう一度シチュエーションを確認します 友人がまた財布をなくしました
最近売っている便利な装置の利用を進めてください 例えば財布をまたなくしたの今月2回目だよ
あなたの電話から物の位置を突き止めることを可能にする あの装置について聞いたことがある
あなたの財布にそれを入れてみたら?など
さあ友人にこう聞かれますよ
あなたならどのように言いますか?
それではここでデイビッドさんの答えを聞きましょう
では内容を順番に確認しましょう
財布をまたなくしたの?今月2回目だよ。
Lost Your Walletは多動型。
Have you heard of that gadget that enables you to locate things from your phone?
Why don't you put one in your wallet?
あなたの電話から物の位置を突き止めることを可能にするあの装置について聞いたことがある?
あなたの財布にそれを入れてみたら?
hear ofは何々について聞く
enables以下はtoふてしを用いた目的を説明型
youがto以下に進むことを可能にする
それではデイビッドさんの答えをもう一度聞きましょう
You lost your wallet again? That's the second time this month.
Have you heard of that gadget that enables you to locate things from your phone?
Why don't you put one in your wallet?
Hey guys, what kind of videos do you like to watch?
Well, me, I usually watch cooking videos
It gives me my inspiration for that night's dinner
How about you, Rosa?
You know, I don't really watch videos anymore
When I feel like I want to watch something
I just go in my living room and look out into the garden
It's entertaining enough
なるほどね、僕は目高ですかね
というわけで今日はこのへんで
Bye